We're now ready to introduce you to the second and final type of layer
我们现在可以介绍第二种 也是最后一种层级类型了
that we'll need to introduce before building our own convolutional neural networks.
然后才能构建自己的卷积神经网络
These so-called pooling layers often take convolutional layers as input.
这些所谓的池化层经常将卷积层当做输入
Recall that a convolutional layer is a stack of feature
卷积层是指特征映射堆栈
maps- where we have one feature map for each filter.
每个过滤器对应一个特征映射
A complicated dataset with
具有很多不同的对象类别的复杂数据集
many different object categories will require a large number of filters,
将需要大量的过滤器
each responsible for finding a pattern in the image.
每个过滤器负责从图片中查找一种规律
More filters means a bigger stack,
过滤器越多 则堆栈越大
which means that the dimensionality of our convolutional layers can get quite large.
意味着卷积层的维度可能会很庞大
Higher dimensionality means we'll need to use more parameters,
维度越高 我们就需要使用更多的参数
which can lead to overfitting.
这样可能会导致过拟合
Thus, we need a method for reducing this dimensionality.
因此 我们需要一种方法来降低维数
This is the role of pooling layers within a convolutional neural network.
这就是卷积神经网络中的池化层所扮演的角色
We'll focus on two different types of pooling layers.
我们将侧重于两者不同类型的池化层
The first type is a max pooling layer.
第一种类型是最大池化层
Max pooling layers will take a stack of feature maps as input.
最大池化层将一组特征映射作为输入
Here we've enlarged and visualized all three of the feature maps.
这里我们放大并可视化了所有三个特征映射
As with convolutional layers,
和卷积层一样
we'll define a window size and stride.
我们将定义窗口大小和 stride
In this case we'll use a window size of two and a stride of two.
这里 窗口大小设为 2 stride 也设为 2
To construct the max pooling layer,
要构建最大池化层
we'll work with each feature mapped separately.
我们将单独处理每个特征映射
Let's begin with the first feature map.
先从第一个特征映射开始
We start with our window in the top left corner of the image.
从图片的左上角开始移动窗口
The value of the corresponding node in the max pooling layer is
最大池化层中对应的节点值计算方法是：
calculated by just taking the maximum of the pixels contained in the window.
拿出窗口中包含的最大像素
In this case we had a 1, 9, 5,
这里 我们的窗口中有像素
and 4 in our window,
1 9 5 和 4
so 9 was the maximum.
因此最大值是 9
If we continue this process and do it for all of our feature maps,
如果针对所有特征映射继续这一流程
the output is a stack with the same number of feature maps,
则输出是一组具有相同数量的特征映射
but each feature map has been reduced in width and height.
但是每个特征映射的宽和高都减小了
In this case the width and height are half of that of the previous convolutional layer.
这里 宽和高是上一个卷积层的一半
Global average pooling is a bit different.
全局平均池化稍微有点不同
For a layer of this type we specify neither window size nor stride.
对于这种类型的层级 我们既不指定窗口大小 也不指定 stride
This type of pooling is a more extreme type of dimensionality reduction.
这是一种更极端的降低维度的池化类型
It takes a stack of feature maps and computes
它获得一堆特征映射
the average value of the nodes for each map in the stack.
并计算其中每个映射的节点均值
As before, we'll work with each feature map
和之前一样 我们将单独处理每个特征映射
separately beginning with the first feature map.
并从第一个特征映射开始
To get the average value of the nodes we first sum up all the values which yields 80.
要计算节点的均值 我们首先对所有值求和 结果是 80
Then we divide by the total number of nodes, which is 16.
然后除以节点总数 16
This yields five, which is the value for the node here.
结果是 5 即这个节点的值
Repeating the process for the remaining two feature maps,
然后对剩下的两个特征映射重复相同的流程
we get two values of four.
两个值都是 4
Our final output is a stack of feature maps
最终输出是一堆特征映射
where each feature map has been reduced to a single value.
每个特征映射都缩减成一个值
In this way we see that
这样我们可以看出
a global average pooling layer takes a 3D array and turns it into a vector.
全局平均池化将三维数组变成了向量
Here we have a vector with three entries.
这里的向量有三个条目
Let's summarize what we've learned with the food analogy.
我们用一盘食物做比喻 对所学的知识进行总结
We'll think of a convolutional layer as a stack of
我们可以将卷积层看做一堆煎饼
pancakes with one pancake for each feature map.
每个煎饼表示一个特征映射
Pooling layers take that stack and give us back a stack with the same number of
池化层获取这堆煎饼 并返回具有相同数量的一堆煎饼
pancakes except the output pancakes are smaller in width and height.
但是输出煎饼的宽和高变小了
Non-global pooling layers represent a moderate reduction in pancake size.
非全局池化层表示煎饼大小的适中降低
Where each pancake is generally about half as
每个煎饼大概是
tall and half as wide as its corresponding input pancake.
对应输入煎饼宽和高的一半
The global pooling layers reduce each input pancake to essentially an output crumb.
全局池化层相当于将输入煎饼输出后变成了面包屑
But, we still have one crumb for each input pancake.
但是每个输入煎饼依然对应一个面包屑
In this video, we've focused on two types of pooling layers,
在此视频中 我们重点讲解了两种类型的池化
but feel free to read about the others in the Keras documentation linked below.
欢迎阅读下方链接的 Keras 文档 了解其他池化类型